The box model.
盒模型
Doesn't it seem like everything comes in boxes with the web?
想像一下 web 页面好像就是由很多个不同的盒子组成的？
The box model is the foundation of layout on the web,
盒模型是网页布局的基础
it's the conceptual model that code and browsers
它是浏览器根据代码来
follow to visualize the content of a webpage.
渲染视觉内容的一种概念模型
At the highest level,
宏观来说
the box model represents every HTML element in a rectangular box,
盒模型将所有 HTML 元素视做一个矩形盒子
and this box has a number of properties that decide how it's displayed.
同时通过一系列属性来定义它具体如何显示
Every element you make uses the box model,
你遇见的所有元素都在使用盒模型
and each element will be given a width,
每个元素会有一个宽度
a height, a margin,
高度 外边距
a border, and padding.
边框以及内边距等等
Now, width and height are probably familiar and self-explanatory,
宽度和高度你应该一眼就能看出什么意思
but for the other properties associated with the box model,
对于其他盒模型相关的属性
let's take a quick look at some code in the browser to get
让我们先在浏览器中看一些代码
a better idea of what we're talking about in action.
以便让你更好地理解它们是什么意思
So here, I'm going to start by creating an element.
这里 我们先来创建一个元素
I'll say div class equals box.
一个有着 box 类名的 div
Let's make sure it's up. It is,
确保一下它正常显示
and then let's add some style.
然后 让我们添加一些样式
So let's say our box has a width of 300 pixels,
给 box 元素设定 300 像素的宽度
a height of 500 pixels.
和 500 像素的高度
Let's say it has a border,
同时 给它一个边框（border）
so we can see of 2px solid.
设置为 2 个像素 实线
This is a grade that I like.
我喜欢这个样式
Now that we could see, we have our box.
现在我们已经有了一个 box 元素
Now, I'm just going to create a second box
我们继续创建第二个 box
because one of the things I want us to look at
因为我们主要想查看的是
is the margin and padding that comes with these.
它的外边距（margin）和内边距（padding）
So here we can see our elements,
所以在这里我们找到我们的元素
box 1, box 2.
box 1、box 2
Here, we could see the element size,
这里 我们可以看见元素的尺寸
we could see the padding,
也可以看见内边距
the border, and the margin.
边框 以及 外边距
So let's try adding some margin explicitly,
让我们显式添加一些外边距
and you could see that the margin is one of the things that will set our boxes apart.
然后你可以看到 外边距把不同元素分隔开了
So now, we can see that our box has the blue matches up to here,
这里的蓝色区域和这里的部分是对应起来的
300 by 500, and the margin,
300 乘以 500
we could see here in orange.
外边距是橙色显示的部分
So let's add some padding just to see what the padding does too.
让我们再添加一些内边距 看看它有什么作用
So now, we can see the blue represents the width and the height,
现在 我们可以看到这里的蓝色区域代表着宽度和高度
we could see the green is the padding and the orange is the margin of our elements.
这里的绿色区域则代表着内边距 外边距则用橙色表示了出来
Because these are both class box,
因为它们的类名都是 box
we could see that they're set to be the same.
所以它们是完全相同的样式
Now, if we wanted to override it,
如果我们想要覆盖的话
remember, we can always use inline styles.
我们可以使用内联样式
So maybe on my second box,
在我们的第二个 box 中
I want to say style attribute equals,
我们设置一下 style 属性
and I actually want to give it
通过内联样式
a border that's red inline styles, border that's red.
我想给它一个红色的边框
Now, we could see we have the blue Python width, green padding.
现在我们可以看到有蓝色的宽度和高度 绿色的内边距
We could see our slight border,
以及一点点的边框
and then we see our margin.
最后是我们的外边距
This is the box model, quite literally,
这就是盒模型 跟字面意思一样
boxes inside of boxes. Sound good?
一个套一个的盒子 Ok 吗？